<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>David Simão Blog</title>
        <link>https://madoke.org/blog</link>
        <description>David Simão Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The complete software engineer]]></title>
            <link>https://madoke.org/blog/the-complete-software-engineer</link>
            <guid>the-complete-software-engineer</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Technology and automation are tapping into every possible industry and the demand for software engineers has never been higher.  Building successful companies gets harder every time because of all the competition creating new challenges everywhere, and as more people try to get themselves a good slice of the giant IT pizza, the need for differentiation between engineers becomes crucial to get a taste of that pepperoni.]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Thoughts on software engineering leadership]]></title>
            <link>https://madoke.org/blog/thoughts-on-swe-leadership</link>
            <guid>thoughts-on-swe-leadership</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Roughly 3 years have passed since I became a lead software engineer (or tech lead) and it's been an exciting run with many achievements and pitfalls. In this article, I try to synthesise the most important lessons I've learned so far on my journey, hoping that they can be useful to other leads who are trying to develop their craft. Having headed a couple of teams until now, I still have a lot to learn, but I certainly do approach things in a different way than I did some years ago, and the results present themselves in the most unexpected ways. There’s no secret formula for leadership, It's a learning process pretty much like working with a new language or framework. I started off by reading some blogs and books, but the greatest lessons actually came from trial and error, and constructive feedback from others.]]></description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>